My name is Emmanuel Newman C.
I am a Nigerian from Anambra State.
I reside in Gabon.
My testimony goes like this:
I was suffering from the spirit of lust, masturbation,
smoking, womanising and drinking.
With all these, I became a Christian without being delivered.
I preached the Word of God and would evangelise.
Listen to that statement:
He said he became a Christian without being delivered
and that is thousand people today.
When you are a Christian and you are not delivered, you are religious.
There is a difference between Christianity and religion.
You don't need to be delivered before you become a religious man
but you need to be delivered to become a Christian.
Christianity is all about a relationship with Jesus
and Jesus is the Deliverer.
For you to have a relationship with Him, you need to be delivered.
The difference between Christianity and religion is:
Christianity - you need to be delivered to become a Christian.
You don't need to be delivered before you become what? - A religious man.
That is why today, if you see twenty people today gather and they say they are Christians,
out of these twenty, hardly one of them is a Christian.
All nineteen are religious people.
What are the characteristics of a religious man?
One of the characteristics is you see them always complaining.
"I have headache. I have pain. I have this. I have that."
In the face of their faith, they believe that their pain or trouble will kill them.
What else again?
"When is he going? Gradually, he is to go." - You will know he is a religious man.
Religious people always give a time to God.
I was preaching the Gospel and said I was a Christian
but this sin kept on tormenting me.
That masturbation became so much that I saw preaching as just fun
because people loved it but at a time, I gave up.
Through that sin, I went into smoking, drinking and living all kinds of lives.
This thing has cost me a lot of setback in life. I never made it.
Nothing worked for me.
My life became wayward and I started thinking;
this Jesus might be just an ordinary religion, like I understood other religions,
just ordinary belief. Maybe He did not exist because to say the truth,
the miracles we are seeing here, I have not seen them anywhere in the world.
I read so many books during the time when I was preaching
and teaching the Word of God but I had not seen this kind.
One of my friends first of all introduced me to Emmanuel TV.
I said, "No, we have heard about this man!
People said a lot about him.
Forget about it!" But he said, "No, I had to watch this".
I said, "No, I don't want to watch this".
Even in our church, they asked us not to watch all other Christian channels,
especially like The SCOAN.
One day, I visited one of my friends and he was watching Emmanuel TV.
I heard a message while watching Emmanuel TV that said,
"If you make a mistake as we all do, don't run from God, run to God".
I saw the message and told the guy, "Please, don't switch off this station",
I just wanted to see whether it was the man of God, T.B. Joshua, that was saying this.
I thought he must be saying something important so I watched the message.
I heard a lot of messages that I had not heard before - very slow and powerful.
This message turned my life around.
I asked my friend, "How can I get this station?"
He said, "Just buy a decoder. I will call one of the technicians to place it for you".
I said, "Okay". I had to do everything quickly because that message touched me.
Because of this sin, I was running away from the Word of God.
I didn't like hearing the Word of God.
It made me afraid; I would think God hated me.
This message gave me hope and courage that there was still hope for me.
That even the man of God was saying,
"If we make mistakes as we all do, don't run from God; run to Him".
I said, "Okay, let me see. Since I have run before to God,
the way I claim, but I am still masturbating. So, let me see.
I will just keep on watching this station and see what will happen.
So, I started watching Emmanuel TV.
I saw the miracles that were happening.
The things I had read in the Bible, I started seeing it physically.
I said, "Wow, this might be a film or something. I don't know".
I told one of my friends that what I saw on Emmanuel TV was exactly what the Bible said.
He said, "It is happening". I asked, "In my country, Nigeria?" and he said, "Yes, in Nigeria".
I said, "Ah!"
I said that now I wanted to see the power of God.
I sat down. I was with my packet of cigarettes, still living the same life
but the one thing that kept me going on was when he said, "If we make mistakes,
we should not run from God". I said, "God, I will not run from You now.
I will watch You until You change my life".
I was watching Emmanuel TV.
So when the man of God said, "Lay your hand on the screen and pray",
I was still doing the same things. I stubbed my cigarette.
Even my brother can bear witness.
One of my brothers came to my sitting room and said,
"You are watching the things of God and you are still smoking.
You do not respect God".
I said, "No, this is beyond me. It is God that will do it".
So, I went to the screen and laid my hand on the screen
while the man of God was praying.
Immediately something left me but I didn't take it as anything.
So, I just went away. The decision just came to me. I packed my cigarettes.
There was one in my kitchen, sitting room, even inside my car.
I went down to the car and took the packet there.
I packed everything and threw it in the dustbin.
I went to my room because CDs of pornographic films filled my house.
I just picked them up and threw them into the dustbin
and said I wouldn't do this again.
I just left and forgot about everything.
The most surprising thing was cigarettes.
I left, forgot about the prayer and went to my normal business.
I didn't smoke. This started around three o'clock.
I didn't smoke. I even forgot about cigarettes 'til the next day.
I went with my friends to a restaurant. We went to go and eat.
My friend was a smoker too. After eating, he bought a stick of cigarettes.
He offered them to me. It was then I remembered. I said, "Please, I won't smoke.
Could you imagine that since yesterday, I laid my hands on Emmanuel TV,
prayed and forgot all about cigarettes".
He said, "Forget about that. We know you. I take sticks but you smoke packets.
How can you say you can just stop cigarettes just like that?"
I said, "No, I won't smoke. Keep your cigarettes".
From there, I started imagining. It was as if I had never smoked before.
This deliverance is real. It is as if I had never smoked before.
So, if you want to be a Christian and you are still struggling with that urge,
it is religious. You just need real deliverance.
Once you are delivered, you would know that you are a different person entirely.
I started looking at myself and wondering what had happened.
It was as if I had never smoked before. I couldn't hold myself.
I started telling people. People were laughing.
People that knew me well said, "You have started again.
We knew you before when you were carrying the Bible.
Now, you have come again".
I said, "No, this one is different.
Before, I just did it myself but now Jesus has decided to take over everything".
It is not drama.
When you just stretch your hand along with me, that is the end!
The Spirit of God will enter you, and you will stop those bad habits!
Now, viewers all over the world, I want to give you; now, it is time.
Listen once again. You have listened to our brother; receive yours now.
As you watch God's power,
never a sickness Jesus cannot heal; never a disease Jesus cannot cure.
As you watch God's power, never a burden Jesus cannot bear.
As you watch God's power, trust Him; your situation will change.
Are you sick? Touch Him; you will be healed, in the name of Jesus!
Are you poor? Be blessed, in the name of Jesus Christ!
Whatever name you call that sickness, never a sickness Jesus cannot heal!
Be healed, in the name of Jesus Christ!
Believe Him; your needs will be met, in the name of Jesus Christ!
If you have eaten through dreams or from the table of your enemy, adversary
or from the table of demons, be delivered, in the name of Jesus Christ!
Be washed away by the blood of Jesus Christ!
In the name of Jesus!
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Thank you, brother. Just give your advice to the world.
My advice to the world is I want them to watch Emmanuel TV.
We believe you have been inspired by the clip you have just watched.
Click here to subscribe to witness more of God's power at work in our generation today
and stay up-to-date with the latest prophecies, deliverances,
sermons and testimonies from The SCOAN.
Emmanuel TV - Changing lives, Changing nations, and Changing the world.
RV: Mel Flowers 24/03/2019